ILGWU. Local 22 minutes, 5780/036
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU. Local 22 minutes
1932-1972.
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 22 (New York, N.Y.)
5780/036
1 collection
4 linear feet
Minutes.
Records of International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union Local 22, Dressmakers Union. Includes minutes of Executive Board, Membership, and Grievance Committee meetings.
5490728
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel
Compiled by:
Melissa Holland
Date completed:
1996
EAD encoding:
Cheryl Beredo, April 2011
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was founded in New York City in 1900 by mostly Socialist immigrant workers who sought to unite the various crafts in the growing women's garment industry. The union soon reflected changes in the sector and rapidly organized thousands of unskilled and semi-skilled women, mostly Jewish and Italian young immigrants. Exemplifying the "new unionism," the ILGWU led two of the most widespread and best-known industrial strikes of the early Twentieth Century: the shirtwaist makers' strike of 1909 in New York City and the cloak makers' strike of 1910 in Chicago. The union also tried to adapt to the fragmented and unstable nature of the industry. It adopted the "protocol of peace," a system of industrial relations that attempted to ensure stability and limit strikes and production disruption by providing for an arbitration system to resolve disputes.
The ILGWU exemplified the European-style social unionism of its founding members. They pursued bread and butter issues but provided educational opportunities, benefits, and social programs to union members as well. In 1919, the ILGWU became the first American union to negotiate an unemployment compensation fund that was contributed to by its employers. The ILGWU also pioneered in the establishment of an extremely progressive health care program for its members which included not only regional Union Health Centers but also a resort for union workers, known as Unity House. The Union also had an imaginative and pioneering Education Department which not only trained workers in traditional union techniques, but provided courses in citizenship and the English language.
David Dubinsky, an immigrant from Belarus who came to the US in 1911, provided strong leadership that led to unprecedented growth in the union during his presidency from 1932 to 1966. He led the union through successful internal anti-communist struggles, built on the ascendancy of industrial unionism by encouraging the formation of the Committee for Industrial Organization, and helped the union become an important political force in New York City and state politics, and in the national Democratic Party and Liberal Party as well.
In the period following the Second World War, the union suffered a decline in membership as manufacturers avoided unionization and took advantage of less expensive labor by moving shops from the urban centers in the northeast to the south, and later abroad. The ethnic and racial character of the ILGWU also changed as European immigrants were supplanted by Asians, Latin Americans, African- Americans, and immigrants from the Caribbean.
In July 1995 the ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU) at a joint convention, forming UNITE (Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees). At the time the new union had a membership of about 250,000 in the United States, Canada, and Puerto Rico.
Biographical / Historical
Local 22 of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), also known as the Dressmakers' Union, was chartered in December 1920 and based in New York, New York.
Scope and Contents
Records of International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union Local 22, Dressmakers Union. Includes minutes of Executive Board, Membership, and Grievance Committee meetings.
Conditions Governing Access
The ILGWU Records, except for publications and materials produced for publication, are restricted. Materials created prior to twenty years from the current date are open to researchers only with prior written permission from the Director of the Kheel Center; materials created during the past twenty-years are closed; the minutes of the General Executive Board are closed. For more information contact the Kheel Center.
Related Materials
5780. ILGWU Records
5780/014. ILGWU. Local 22. Charles Zimmerman papers
5780/014 P. ILGWU. Local 22. Charles Zimmerman photographs
5780/015. ILGWU. Local 22 records
5780/057. ILGWU. Local 22. Education Department records
5780/057 P. ILGWU. Local 22. Education Department photographs
5780/067. ILGWU. Local 22. Israel Breslow papers
General
"Permanent deposit"
Arrangement
Series I. Executive Board Meetings, 1934-1972
Series II. Committee Meetings, 1943-1967
Sub-series A. Grievance Committee, 1943-1952
Sub-series B. Membership Meetings, 1964-1967
Women's clothing industry -- United States; Women's clothing industry -- New York (State) -- New York; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- United States; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York; Clothing workers -- United States; Clothing workers -- New York (State) -- New York; Industrial relations -- United States; Industrial relations -- New York (State) -- New York; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 22 (New York, N.Y.)
5490728
- Series I. Executive Board Meetings, 1934-1972
  - Executive Board. Minutes., 1934 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    January 1, 1934 - December 30, 1934
  - Executive Board. Minutes., 1935 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    January 1, 1935 - December 31, 1935
  - Executive Board. Minutes., 1936 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Vol. 6. January 1, 1936 - December 31, 1936
  - Executive Board. Minutes., 1937 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Vol. 7. January 1, 1937 - December 31, 1937
  - Executive Board. Minutes., 1938 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Vol. 8. January 1, 1938 - December 31, 1938
  - Executive Board. Minutes., 1939 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Vol. 9. January 1, 1939 - December 31, 1939
  - Executive Board. Minutes., 1940 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Vol. X. January 2, 1940 - December 17, 1940
  - Executive Board. Minutes., 1941 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Vol. XI. January 7, 1941 - December 23, 1941
  - Executive Board. Minutes., 1942 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Vol. XII. January 12, 1942 - December 22, 1942
  - Executive Board. Minutes., 1943 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Vol. XIII. January 5, 1943 - December 21, 1943
  - Executive Board. Minutes., 1944 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Vol. XIV. January 4, 1944 - December 11, 1945
  - Executive Board. Minutes., 1945-1947 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Vol. XV. January 8, 1946 - December 23, 1947
  - Executive Board. Minutes., 1948-1949 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Vol. XVI. January 18, 1948 - December 20, 1949
  - Executive Board. Minutes., 1950-1951 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Vol. XVII. January 10, 1950 - December 18, 1951
  - Executive Board. Minutes., 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Vol. XVIII. January 8, 1952 - December 15, 1953
  - Executive Board. Minutes., 1954-1956 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Vol. XIX. January 5, 1954 - December 18, 1956
  - Executive Board. Minutes., 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Vol. XX. January 8, 1957 - December 23, 1958
  - Executive Board. Minutes., 1959-1960 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Vol. XXI. January 6, 1959 - December 20, 1960
  - Executive Board. Minutes., 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Vol. XXII. January 3, 1961 - December 12, 1962
  - Executive Board. Minutes., 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Vol. XXIII. January 8, 1963 - December 22, 1964
  - Executive Board. Minutes., 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Vol. XXIV. January 5, 1965 - December 27, 1966
  - Executive Board. Minutes., 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Vol. XXV. January 10, 1967 - December 26, 1968
  - Executive Board. Minutes., 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Vol. XXVI. January 21, 1969 - December 29, 1970
  - Executive Board. Minutes., 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Vol. XXVII. January 19, 1971 - December 26, 1972
- Series II. Committee Meetings, 1943-1967
  - Subseries A. Grievance Committee, 1943-1952
    - Grievance Committee. Minutes., 1943 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      Vol. XI. January 4, 1943 - December 20, 1943
    - Grievance Committee. Minutes., 1944 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      Vol. XII. 1944
    - Grievance Committee. Minutes., 1945 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      Vol. XIII. 1945
    - Grievance Committee. Minutes., 1946 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      Vol. XIV. 1946
    - Grievance Committee. Minutes., 1947 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      Vol. XV. 1947
    - Grievance Committee. Minutes., 1948-1952 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      Vol. XVI. 1948 - 1952 Inclusive
  - Sub-series B. Membership Meetings, 1964-1967
    - General Membership. Minutes., 1964-1967 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      May 13, 1964 - March 1, 1967